RG 030, Council of Defense
Connecticut State Library
- Series 10. Publicity Department
  - 47. Lists of "Makers of Public Sentiment", 1917
    - Card list
      - Hartford County: Hartford - Windsor Locks (Box 415)
      - Litchfield County: Barkhamsted - Plymouth (Box 415)
      - Litchfield County: Plymouth - Woodbury (Box 416)
      - Middlesex County: Chester - Westbrook (Box 416)
      - New Haven County: Ansonia - Madison (Box 416)
      - Neew Haven County: Meriden - North Branford (Box 417)
      - New Haven County: North Haven - Woodbridge (Box 418)
      - New London County: Bozrah - Norwich (Box 418)
      - New London County: Old Lyme - Waterford (Box 419)
      - Tolland County: Andover - Willington (Box 419)
      - Windham County: Brooklyn - Woodstock (Box 419)
      - Commercial travelers (Box 419-420)
    - Typed lists (Box 256)
      Perhaps drawn from the cards.
  - 48. Press bulletins, 1917 November-1919 January
    Mimeographed bulletins and releases for the press.
    - Numerical
      - 1 - 416, 1917 November 16-1918 April 4 (Box 257)
      - 417 - 874, 1918 April 6-1919 January 11 (Box 258)
      - Index by subject (Box 421)
    - Subjects
      - Prof. Henderson of Yale re Experiments (Box 259)
      - Mr. Chandler (Box 259)
      - Catechism (Box 259)
      - Committee chairmen re expense account & budget; Council automobile (Box 259)
      - Mr. Alsop - Mr. Chandler to be at Litchfield November 30, 1917 (Box 259)
      - Mr. Chandler to go to Putnam December 1, 1917 (Box 259)
      - College statistics, 1917 October 27 (Box 259)
      - Chamber of Commerce rally week (Box 259)
      - Suggestions Publicity Committee, 1917 June 11 (Box 259)
      - U.S. Councils of Defense (Box 259)
      - Fourth of July (Box 259)
      - Foreign language newspapers (Box 259)
      - Correspondence made in Connecticut war interviews (Box 259)
      - Speech - Munitions - Sir Stephenson Kent (Box 259)
      - Window display - Liberty Loan (Box 259)
      - Advertising Report - Div. Moving Pictures (Box 259)
      - Bulletin to Manufacturers re correspondence, etc. (Box 259)
      - Occupational exemption from draft (Box 259)
      - Printed bulletins, employers, etc. (Box 259)
      - Town chairmen - mayors and wardens - Proclamation departing soldiers (Box 259)
      - Mr. Maddock - Division of War Rallies re poster, hand-bills, etc. (Box 259)
      - Registration suggestions (Box 259)
      - Rendezvous (Box 259)
      - Bulletin #21 - Registration (Box 259)
      - Rules for Mailing Department (Box 259)
      - Nov. 20 Statewide rallies - Confirmation blanks, time, place, speakers (Box 259)
      - Nov. 22 - State-wide war rallies "Instructions to printer" (Box 259)
      - Nov. 26 - To town chairmen Windham, Hartford, New Haeven and Litchfield Counties (Box 259)
      - Nov. 21 - Statewide rallies - To town chairmen (material for rallies) (Box 259)
      - Nov. 6 - Mr. Chandler - re -Scoville Mfg Co. Bulletin (Box 259)
      - Nov. 15 - Invitation to speakers meeting November 20, 1917 (Box 259)
      - Bulletin #22 - Filling state quota (Box 259)
      - Protest against draft estimates (Box 259)
      - Smith-Hughes Bill (Box 259)
      - Special Representatives (Box 259)
      - Oct. 5 - Woman's Activities - Traveler's Aid (Box 259)
      - Nov. 3 - Woman's activities - re Meeting December 4 or 6th (Box 259)
      - Emergency relief organizations (Box 259)
  - 49. Card list of newspapers, circa 1918 (Box 421)
    Card lists of papers and their staff who served as Council representatives.
  - 50. Bulletin board invoices and lists, 1917-1918
    - Invoices (Box 260-261)
      Paid and unpaid for the sale of bulletin boards.
    - Card list of persons displaying Council of Defense bulletin boards (Box 421)
  - 51. Poster distribution material, 1917-1918 (Box 262)
    Post card pledges to display posters, and book record of distribution of posters.
    Examples of Council of defense posters are in the Pictorial Collection (RG 064) and in the Classified file (Item 1).
  - 52. Lantern slides, 1917-1918
    Glass slides probably used in motion picture theaters or lecture halls. Subjects include "Army", food conservation, shipbuilding, aviation.
    Arranged numerically and listed on cards.
    - A-1 - G-23 (Box 263)
    - G-24 - G-95 (Box 264)
    - G-96 - G-173 (Box 265)
    - H-1 - M-6 (Box 266)
    - Card listing (Box 422)
  - 53. Motion picture files, 1918
    Correspondence, memoranda, address lists, etc. pertaining to the procurement, distribution and exhibition of motion picture films.
    - General and administrative correspondence (Box 267)
      Grouped roughly by subject.
    - Correspondence with town or local officials
      Arranged by county thereafter by town.
      - Fairfield County, Hartford County (Box 268)
      - Litchfield County, Middlesex County, New Haven County (Box 269)
      - New London County, Tolland County, Windham County (Box 270)
    - Card list of showings (Box 270)
    - Invoices, checks, statements (Box 271)
    - Account books, ticket samples, etc. (Box 272)
  - 54. Clipping and Research Bureau file, 1917-1918
    - Correspondence (Box 273)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 274-280)
      Grouped by subject but not otherwise arranged.
    - "Pamphlets from desk", 6 large envelopes (Box 281-284)
      Box 281 contains a list.
    - Assorted items (Box 285-287)
      Clippings, pictures, statistics on items published, movies circulated, etc.
  - 54. Cuts and plates, circa 1918
    Copper and lead cuts and printing plates, used in the Council or distributed by it to publishers. Most are publicity items - display ads, questionnaires, form letters, etc. and many are in foreign languages.
    - A-1 - C-8 (Box 288)
    - C-9 - D-17 (Box 289)
    - D-18 - E-10 (Box 290)
    - G-7 - K-4 (Box 291)
    - Unlisted (Box 292)
    - Oversize (Box 292)
      Stored in flat box.
    - Card listing (Box 422)
  - 56. Music Department file, 1917-1918
    - General correspondence
      - 1917 October-1918 May (Box 294)
      - 1918 June-December (Box 295)
    - Town correspondence
      - A - L (Box 296)
      - M - R (Box 297)
      - S - Z (Box 298)
    - Music and miscellaneous (Box 299)
  - 57. War Rallies Division correspondence, 1917-1918
    Letters, notes and memoranda pertaining to the recruiting, briefing, and assignment of speakers for rallies and on related subjects.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent in five files by date.
    - 1917 November 1-1918 February 20 (Box 300)
    - 1918 February 21-May 1 (Box 301)
    - 1918 May-July (Box 302)
    - 1918 August-October (Box 303)
    - 1918 October-November (Box 304)
  - 58. War Rallies Division speakers' lists and briefing materials, 1917-1918 (Box 305)
  - 59. War Rallies Division "Collected materials", 1917-1918 (Box 306-307)
  - 60. Four Minute Man correspondence, 1917-1918
    Letters pertaining to the administration of the program for providing patriotic speakers in Connecticut.
    - Washington (Committee on Public Information)
      - 1918 January-June (Box 308)
      - 1918 July-December (Box 309)
    - Local chairmen, 2 files
      - Ansonia - Manchester (Box 310)
      - Meriden - Norwich (Box 311)
      - Salisbury - Winsted (Box 312)
      - Second file (Box 313)
    - Miscellaneous and unfiled (Box 314-315)
      Partially chronological.
  - 61. Four Minute Man bulletins and circulars, 1917-1918 (Box 316)
    Washington and Connecticut materials distributed to state and local officials.
  - 62. Four Minute Man lists, 1917-1918 (Box 423)
    Card lists of town chairmen, speakers and translators.
    Several groups (some duplication), each by county and thereunder by town, or by language.
  - 63. Four Minute Man "Collected materials", 1917-1918 (Box 317-319)
  - 64. Publicity Department "Collected materials", 1917-1918 (Box 320-323)
- Series 11. Soldiers' and Sailors' Information Bureau
  - 65. General file, 1917-1918
    Correspondence and memoranda pertaining to advice and assistance provided to members and former members of the services (Legal, family problems, pension, insurance, disability, etc.)
    - Subject file
      - Addressing letters (Box 324)
      - Alien property custodian (Box 324)
      - Allotments and allowances (Box 324)
      - Alsop, J. W. (Box 324)
      - Enlistments (Box 324)
      - Furloughs for farm service (Box 324)
      - Legal (Box 324)
      - Library War Service (Box 324)
      - Mail (Box 324)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 324)
      - Red Cross chapters (Box 324)
      - Red Cross home service bulletins (Box 324)
      - Sanitary (Box 324)
      - Soldiers addresses (Box 324)
      - Soldiers and Sailors relief (Box 324)
      - Soldiers disabled (Box 325)
      - Soldiers, killed, wounded or missing (Box 324)
      - Training camps (Box 325)
      - War risk insurance (Box 325)
      - War Bureau, Berlin (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Brookfield (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Canton (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Danbury (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Greenwich (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Hartford (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Kent (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Lyme (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Meriden (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Milford (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - New Britain (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - New Haven (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - New London (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Orange (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Plainville (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Shelton (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Somers (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - South Manchester (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Sterling (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Torrington (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Westbrook (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Windsor (Box 325)
      - War Bureau - Woodstock (Box 325)
      - Mr. Fields' file, 2 envelopes (Box 325)
    - Name file
      - A - F (Box 326)
      - F - M (Box 327)
      - N - Z (Box 327)
- Series 12. Transportation Department
  - 66. Classified file, 1917-1918
    This is the portion of the Council of Defense classified file (Item 1 above) pertaining to transportation activities.
    Classified and arranged according to the Council's scheme (N series).
    - N: Transportation general material (Box 329)
    - N06: Hartford Club meeting, 1917 December (Box 329)
    - N06.1: Hartford Club meeting, 1917 December 11 (Box 329)
    - N15: U. S. Railroad Administration orders & circulars (Box 329)
    - N25: Freight (Box 329)
    - N25: Freight clean up, 1918 January (Box 329)
    - N26: X,Y, Z reports - N.Y.N.H & H. Railroad (Box 329-331)
    - N26: Hartford Division (Box 331)
    - N26: Highland Division (Box 331)
    - N26: New London Division (Box 331)
    - N26: New York Division (Box 331)
    - N26: Providence Division (Box 331)
    - N27: New York, New Haven & Hartford Railroad and Central New England Railroad freight embargoes (Box 331)
    - N28: Readjustment of freight rates (Box 332)
    - N29: Council of National Defense Storage Committee, War Industries Board (Box 332)
    - N29: Storage reports (Box 332)
    - N29: Storage canvas - report, 3 folders (Box 332)
    - N29: Home storage of fruits and vegetables (Box 332)
    - N29: Storage during the war (Box 332)
    - N35: Transportation of peaches (Box 332)
    - N36: Shipment of coal (Box 332)
    - N38: Ordering fertilizer (Box 332)
    - N37: Shipment of potatoes (Box 332)
    - N39: Report of flour cars in transit (Box 332)
    - N125: Electric railroads - Bulletins of American Railway Association (Box 332)
    - N125.3: American Electric Railway Association (Box 332)
    - N127: Use of trolley companies to relieve freight congestion (Box 332)
    - N175: Roads (Box 332)
    - N195: Highways transport service (Box 332)
    - N195: Highways Transport Committee - Bulletins, letters, etc. (Box 333)
    - N195: The American City, 1918 September (Box 333)
    - N200: Motor vehicle law - State of Connecticut (Box 333)
    - N201: Motor truck transportation - Correspondence (Box 333)
    - N201: Letters re Motor Truck Express Co. - W. H. Putnam (Box 333)
    - N201: List of truck owners - Meriden (Box 333)
    - N201: Return loads (Box 333)
    - N201: The Commercial Vehicle, 1917 November 1, 1918 March 1, 15, May 15, June 15; 5 issues (Box 333)
    - N201: Engineering News-Record, 1918 August 29 (Box 334)
    - N201: Hartford, 1918 July (Box 334)
    - N201: Hartford, 1918 August (Box 334)
    - N201: Motor Age, 1918 February 28 (Box 334)
    - N201: Motor Age, 1918 March 14 (Box 334)
    - N201: Transfer & Storage, 1918 April (Box 334)
    - N201.05: Press items re Return Loads - Motor truck transportation (Box 334)
    - N201.05: Clippings re motor trucks & return loads (Box 334)
    - N201.07 Lists - return load (Box 334)
    - N201.08: Circular letters re return loads by Connecticut Transportation Department (Box 334)
    - N201.081: Questionnaires (Box 334)
      - Ansonia, Derby, Seymour, Shelton (Box 334)
      - Bristol (Box 334)
      - Bridgeport (Box 334)
      - Danbury (Box 334)
      - Greenwich (Box 334)
      - Haddam (Box 334)
      - Hartford (Box 334)
      - Middletown (Box 334)
      - New Britain (Box 334)
      - New London (Box 334)
      - Norwalk (Box 334)
      - Norwich (Box 334)
      - Waterbury (Box 334)
      - Winsted (Box 334)
    - N201.1: Rural Motor Express (Box 334)
    - N202: Need for greater motor transport labor - National Council of Defense (Box 334)
    - N203: Motor messenger service (Box 334)
    - N203: Auxiliaries (men) (Box 334)
    - N203: Automobiles for transportation of speakers (Box 334)
    - N203: Circular letters - State organization (Box 334)
    - N203: French Band (Box 334)
    - N203: Incorrect maps (Box 335)
    - N203: Majors - Correspondence with (Box 335)
    - N203: Motor messenger service (Box 335)
    - N203: Publicity (Box 335)
    - N203: Quartermaster's Department (Box 335)
    - N203: Questionnaires (Box 335)
    - N203: Reports (Box 335)
    - N203: Col. Russell - Personal correspondence (Box 335)
    - N203: State Board of Health (Box 335)
    - N203: Replies from War Bureaus - Appointment of Captains (Box 335)
    - N203: Replies from Women's Committees (Box 335)
    - N203: Transportation for speakers, etc. (Box 335)
    - N235: Automobiles for secret service work (Box 335)
      Correspondence arranged alphabetically by towns.
    - N301: Shipping (Box 335)
    - N301.1: Navigation on Connecticut River - Freight service between N.Y & Saybrook (Box 335)
    - N301.1: Replies to Saybrok Boat letter, January 3, 1818 (Box 335)
    - N301.1: Saybrook Boat (Box 335)
  - 67. Correspondence, 1917-1918
    Incoming and outgoing letters.
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent with unfiled material at the end.
    - A - Ch (Box 336)
    - Ch - Conn. Council of Defense (Box 337)
    - Connecticut Towns - D (Box 338)
    - E - Mo (Box 339)
    - Mo - R (Box 340)
    - S - Z, unfiled material (Box 341)
  - 68. Truck survey cards, 1917 October (Box 342)
    Completed questionnaire cards from truck owners pertaining to the availability of trucks for "back loads" or for rental.
    Badly unarranged; originally by county and town.
  - 69. Storage survey cards, 1917 (Box 343)
    Form cards, recording contracts held by manufacturers, with "material", time and place of delivery, and storage space available and required.
    Unarranged; originally by town.
  - 70. "Collected materials", 1917-1918 (Box 344)
- Series 13. Fund-raising Activities
  - 71. War Chest study, undated
    Data file on war chest policy and practice in other states.
    - Administration expenses (Box 345)
    - Albany (Box 345)
    - Amount asked for - Detroit (Box 345)
    - Arguments for and against war chest (Box 345)
    - Bookkeeping, ledger forms, etc. (Box 345)
    - Budget - Detroit (Box 345)
    - Census (Box 345)
    - Collection, bookkeeping, accounting - Philadelphia (Box 345)
    - Collection methods (Box 345)
    - Competition (Box 345)
    - Daily meeting (Box 345)
    - Date of campaign (Box 345)
    - Designated gifts (Box 345)
    - Disbursement (Box 345)
    - Dooming (Box 345)
    - Duration of war chest (Box 346)
    - Follow up campaign for subscriptions (Box 346)
    - Form of contribution (Box 346)
    - Inclusion, surrounding towns (Box 346)
    - Labor turnover (Box 346)
    - Local charities (Box 346)
    - Middletown (Box 346)
    - Miscellaneous war chest (Box 346)
    - Officers and their functions (Box 346)
    - Organization of campaign (Box 346)
    - Patriotism - Syracuse, N. Y. (Box 346)
    - Physical side (Box 346)
    - Pledge, Basis of (Box 346)
    - Preliminary - Educational and Publicity (Box 346)
    - Preliminary - Prospect list (Box 346)
    - Productivity (Box 346)
    - Racial teams (Box 346)
    - Red Cross (Box 346)
    - Red Cross membership (Box 346)
    - Relation to State Council of Defense (Box 347)
    - Solicitation of whom (Box 347)
    - Women (Box 347)
    - Workingmen (Box 347)
  - 72. "Collected materials", 1917-1919 (Box 348-355)
    Records deal with the following fund-raising campaigns: War Chest, War Savings Stamps, Boy Scouts, YMCA, United War Work, Liberty Loan, Irish Relief, New East Relief and other "Non-War Appeals".
    Unarranged.
  - 73. Mats for War Savings publicity, undated (Box 356-357)
    Paper-mache mats for magazine and newspaper ads.
- Series 14. Woman's Division
  - 74. Classified file, 1917-1919
    Correspondence, memoranda, clippings, notes, reference materials, etc., pertaining to all Woman's Division
    - List of file titles (Box 358)
    - Clippings concerning the Committee on Woman's Activities, Conn. Division; Organization; Personnel; Departments; etc. (Box 358)
    - T01: Organization of the Woman's Committee Connecticut Division (Box 358)
    - T01: Reorganization (Box 358)
    - T01.16: National Committee re Organization (Box 358)
    - T51: Organization Committee (Box 358)
    - T04: Executive (Box 358)
    - T06: Clippings of Meetings, Conferences held under the auspices of the Woman's Committee or State Council (Box 358)
    - T06: Notices of meetings, State Council, Executive Committee, Committee meetings, etc. (Box 358)
    - T06.1: Arrangements for meetings (Box 358)
    - T07: Addresses (Box 358)
    - T08: Letter including questionnaire re "Back to School" drive (Box 358)
    - T08: Miscellaneous correspondence, "Back to School" drive (Box 358)
    - T08.1: Pamphlets and leaflets re "Back to School: drive (Box 358)
    - T09.8: Reports to Washington re "Back to School" drive (Box 358)
    - T09.16: Reports Woman's Committee to Washington (Box 358)
    - T09.17: Reports Woman's Committee to State Council (Box 358)
    - T09.50: Reports to Executive Meeting, 1919 February 18 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports to Executive Meeting, 1919 January 21 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Connecticut Division, Reports of Organization, 1918 June 4 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Miscellaneous Reports, 1919 January 21 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Connecticut Division, Reports of Organization, 1918 December 5 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports of Executive Meetings previous to 1918 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Departmental Reports for the Bulletin, 1917 December (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 December 10 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 November 12 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 July 15 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 June 18 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Departmental Reports submitted at annual meeting, 1918 June 4 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 May 21 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 April 30 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive Meeting, 1918 April 16 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 April 2 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 March 19 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive Meeting, 1918 March 5 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 February 5 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 January 22 (Box 359)
    - T09.50: Reports submitted to Executive meeting, 1918 January 8 (Box 359)
    - T10.01: Minutes Organization Committee (Box 359)
    - T10.04: Minutes of Executive Committee meetings from June 1918 to (Box 359)
    - T10.04: Minutes of Executive Committee meetings previous to December 1917 (Box 359)
    - T10.04: Minutes of Executive Committee meetings, 1917 December-1918 June (Box 359)
    - T10.17: Minutes of State Council meetings June 1, 1918 to (Box 360)
    - T10.17: Minutes of State Council meetings for year 1917 (Box 360)
    - T10.18: Minutes of Divisional meetings, Connecticut Division (Box 360)
    - T10.20: Minutes Italian (Box 360)
    - T10.51: Minutes Motor Messenger Service (Box 360)
    - T10.52: Minutes Publicity Committee, State Council Woman's Committee (Box 360)
    - T10.59: Minutes Food Production Land Army (Box 360)
    - T10.60: Minutes of Social Services Committee and Housing & Day Nurseries (Box 360)
    - T10.62: Minutes of Committee Meetings Women in Industry Dept. (Box 360)
    - T11: Budgets (Box 361)
    - T 12: Requisitions (Box 361)
    - T12.01: Requisitions (partially unfilled) (Box 361)
    - T14.01 - T14.19: Lists (Box 361)
    - T14.20 - T14.99: Lists (Box 361)
    - T14.100.01: Influential women in towns (Box 361)
    - T14.100 - T14.900: Lists concerning towns (Box 361)
    - T15: Telegrams from the Woman's Committee (Box 361)
    - T15.1: Telegrams to the Woman's Committee (Box 361)
    - T16: Influential Women Fairfield County (Box 361)
    - T16: Shaw, Dr. Anna H., Chairman of the Woman's Committee, Council of National Defense (Box 361)
    - T16: Patterson, Hannah J., Resident Director, Chairman of Registration (Box 361)
    - T 16: Field Division - National Council of Defense (Box 361)
    - T16: Food Administration Department, Miss Ida M. Tarbell, Chairman (Box 361)
    - T16: Women in Industry Department, Miss Agnes Nestor, Chairman; Mrs. James A. Field, Executive Chairman (resigned); Mrs. Samuel Bannister Harding, Executive Chairman (Box 361)
    - T16: State Organization, Mrs. Joseph R. Lamar, Chairman; Miss Ruth Wilson, Assistant to the Chairman (Box 361)
    - Information Department, Miss Elizabeth Green (Box 361)
    - T16: Health and Recreation Department, Mrs. Philip North Moore, Chairman (Box 361)
    - T16: Food Production & Home Economics Dept., Mrs. Stanley McCormick, Chairman (Box 361)
    - T16: Educational Propaganda, Mrs. Martha Evans Martin, Executive Chairman, Mrs. Carrie Chapman Catt, Chairman (Box 361)
    - T16: Public Information (Box 361)
    - T16: News Department, D. M. Reynolds, Assistant Chief, News Section; Miss Emily N. Blair (Box 361)
    - Connecticut State Council of Defense 1918 (Box 362)
    - T16: "Back to School" Drive. Dr. Jessica Peixotto; Mrs. Gulick (Box 362)
    - T16: Clippings re National Woman's Committee (Box 362)
    - T16.1: Woman's Committee Council of National Defense Washington, 1917 (Box 362)
    - T17: Correspondence with State Council (Box 362)
      Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    - T18: Correspondence with Divisional Members re changes in officers of organizations (Box 362)
    - T19: Translation Bureau (Box 363)
    - T19.01: Stanley H. Holmes (Box 363)
    - T19.1: Material for translation (Box 363)
    - T19.1: French translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.2: German translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.3: Italian translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.4: Lithuanian translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.5: Polish translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.6: Russian translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.8: Swedish translations and correspondence (Box 363)